Guide to the John Hay Whitney and Betsey Cushing Whitney Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- John Hay Whitney and Betsey Cushing Whitney, 1849-2008; Series I
  The series documents John Hay Whitney's professional and personal life and Betsey Cushing Whitney's public and private life.
  Betsey Cushing Whitney's correspondence, entirely incoming, dates primarily from the 1980s and 1990s and is from family, friends, and associates. While some relate to her philanthropic activities, much are of a social nature. John Hay Whitney's correspondence, mostly incoming, ranges primarily from 1950 to his death in 1982. It contains some childhood letters sent to him by his father, mother, and sister, as well as correspondence sent and received during his years at Groton and Yale. While his correspondence includes letters from family members, it does not include any from Betsey Cushing Whitney. The letters relate to awards and honors; his business career, including theater and film investments; diplomatic service; political connections; and philanthropic activities.
  The Topical Files section is divided into the following subsections: Ambassadorial, Fine Art Collection, Financial, the New York Herald Tribune, Philanthropy, and Real Estate.
  The most significant material in the Ambassadorial files are the speeches given by John Hay Whitney during his tenure as ambassador to the Court of St. James's between 1957 and 1961. In Personal and Private Correspondence, there are letters Mr. Whitney received from President Dwight D. Eisenhower and Vice President Richard Nixon, the most interesting of which contain discussions between the men regarding Mr. Whitney's decision to purchase the New York Herald Tribune in 1958.
  The Fine Art Collection files contain fairly comprehensive information about John Hay Whitney and Betsey Cushing Whitney's collections of fine art, jewelry, and decorative arts, including inventories of their holdings. Purchases, conservation treatments, appraisals, loans, and exhibitions that featured Whitney art works are also well documented.
  The Financial files are arranged in four sections: Companies, Theatrical Investments, Betsey Cushing Whitney, and John Hay Whitney. Most of the materials in the company files document the later decades of John Hay Whitney's business career and are comprised of correspondence, legal files, and tax documents. There are early materials available on Pioneer Pictures, and a few strategy statements from the early years of J. H. Whitney & Company. Greenstreet Company's investments in "growth" companies are well represented. Information on Betsey Cushing Whitney's investments in Irene M. Selznick Company productions in the 1950s can be found in her personal files. There is an itemized listing of John Hay Whitney's estate at the time of his death in his personal files.
  The New York Herald Tribune files contain correspondence concerning Whitney Communications Corporation's purchase of the newspaper in 1958; files about labor strikes at the paper in 1962 and 1963; and correspondence and topical files regarding the paper's closing in 1966. There are also minute books from the founding of New York Herald Tribune predecessors: the Tribune Association (circa 1880s) and the New York Tribune (circa 1960s).
  Ledgers provide the most useful information in the Philanthropy section about organizations to which Betsey Cushing Whitney and John Hay Whitney contributed. There is additional material related to their political contributions that also documents John Hay Whitney's involvement with the Republican Party at both the national and state levels.
  The Real Estate files contain correspondence, blueprints, floor plans, and appraisals of Whitney properties in New York City; New York state; London; Georgia; and to a lesser extent, Virginia. These materials provide researchers with a rich documentation of the purchase, maintenance, and preservation of Whitney family properties dating back to the 1920s.
  The Biographical section begins with an extensive run of newspaper clippings that span 1901 to 1999. Betsey Cushing Whitney's daily logs and date books are compilations of personal and public appointments. John Hay Whitney's files include an extensive run of speeches that he gave on a range of topics. There is documentation on the writing of Jock: The Life and Times of John Hay Whitney, the full-length biography by E. J. Kahn, Jr., published in 1981, including comments by daughters Kate Roosevelt Whitney and Sara Roosevelt Wilford. The section also includes a short biography of John Hay Whitney prepared by the Paley Foundation.
  - Correspondence
    - Whitney, Betsey Cushing
      - General
        - A, 1983-1997 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
        - B, 1961-1997, undated (Box 1, Folder 3-6)
        - C, 1956-1998 (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
        - D, 1961-1996 (Box 2, Folder 4-5)
        - E, 1952-1995 (Box 2, Folder 6-7)
        - F, 1961-1996 (Box 2, Folder 8-9)
        - G, 1956-1997, undated (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
        - H, 1955-1996 (Box 3, Folder 3-5)
        - I, 1961, 1991-1993, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
        - J, 1956-1961, 1982-1996, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
        - K, 1962-1998, undated (Box 3, Folder 8-9)
        - L, 1961-1997 (Box 4, Folder 1-3)
        - M, 1945-1997, undated (Box 4, Folder 4-6)
        - Mc, 1983-1997 (Box 4, Folder 7)
        - N, 1982-1997 (Box 4, Folder 8)
        - O, 1982-1995 (Box 5, Folder 1)
        - P, 1954-1997, undated (Box 5, Folder 2-3)
        - R, 1956-1996 (Box 5, Folder 4-6)
        - Requests, declined, 1977-1995 (Box 5, Folder 7-9)
        - S, 1955-1998, undated (Box 6, Folder 1-3)
        - T, 1982-1997 (Box 6, Folder 4-5)
        - U, 1985-1990 (Box 6, Folder 6)
        - V, 1983-1996 (Box 6, Folder 7)
        - W, 1959-1998 (Box 7, Folder 1-3)
        - Z, 1985-1997 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Unidentified, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Alsop, Tish and Stewart, 1971-1974 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Astaire, Fred, 1984-1988 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - Birthdays
        Includes birthday cards, party information, copies of invitations and photographs of Betsey Cushing Whitney's birthday celebrations.
        - 80th birthday, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 8)
        - 85th birthday, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 9)
        - 87th birthday, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - Blair House redecorating, 1970-1972 (Box 7, Folder 11)
      - Booth, Geoffrey, 1983-1992 (Box 7, Folder 12)
      - Bowes-Lyon, John, 1984-1992 (Box 7, Folder 13)
      - Brewster, Kingman, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 14)
      - Brigham and Women's Hospital, 1988-1995 (Box 7, Folder 15)
      - Brooks School, 1982-1998 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Bush, George, 1989-1992 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Cartier, 1986-1987 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Chamber Music Society of Lincoln Center, 1990-1991 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Chambers, Ginny and Ambrose, 1971-1974 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Channel 13, 1983-1988 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Chauncey, Henry "Sam", 1991-1997 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - Christ Church in Manhasset, New York, 1985-1989 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Christmas cards received, 1994-1998 (Box 8, Folder 9-10)
      - Christmas cards sent, samples, Circa 1950-1996 (Box 8, Folder 11-13)
      - Cushing, Harvey
        - General, Circa 1970-1990 (Box 9, Folder 1-4)
        - Memorabilia, 1992-1993 (Box 9, Folder 5)
        - Peter Bent Brigham Hospital, Boston, Massachusetts, Cushing celebration, 1989 September 24 (Box 9, Folder 6)
        - Plaque, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 7)
        - Program at Greentree, 1990 May 13 (Box 9, Folder 8)
        - Stamp
          - Celebration, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 1)
          - Issuance, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 2-3)
          - Unveiling of, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - Cushing, Harvey W., 1994-1996 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - Cushing, Kirke and Janet, 1991-1998 (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - Cushing, Michael, 1996-1998 (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Defense Advisory Sub-Committee, 1955 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - Dogs, 1983-1994 (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - Donation of John M. Hay materials to Brown University, 1986-1994 (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - Eisenhower, Dwight D., Circa 1950-1960 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Eisenhower Library, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Eisenhower, Mamie, 1954-1960 (Box 11, Folder 3-4)
      - Elizabeth II, Queen of Great Britain, 1952-1954, 1960 (Box 11, Folder 5-6)
      - Estate of
        - General, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 7)
        - Trust, 1982-1985 (Box 11, Folder 8)
        - Wills and bequests, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - Etting, Gloria, 1984-1998 (Box 11, Folder 10)
      - Family, general, 1959-1992 (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
      - Fosburgh, Mary Cushing (Betsey's sister)
        - Death, 1978-1980 (Box 12, Folder 3)
        - Memorial service, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - Frere, Wallace, 1982-1995 (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - Friends, general, 1951-1995 (Box 12, Folder 6-7)
      - Fritchey, Clayton and Polly, 1982-1995 (Box 12, Folder 8)
      - Gendel, Anna, 1988-1998 (Box 12, Folder 9)
      - Genealogy, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 10)
      - Givenchy, Hubert de, 1984-1997 (Box 12, Folder 11)
      - Gospa, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 12)
      - Graham, Katharine, 1982-1988 (Box 12, Folder 13)
      - Groton School, 1982-1990 (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - Guion, Connie, 1957-1990 (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
      - Hancock, Dell, 1991-1994 (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - Herlihy, Maud, 1984-1987, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - Higginbotham, A. Leon, Jr., 1991-1998 (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - Hip replacement get well messages, 1983,1989 (Box 13, Folder 6-8)
      - Holiday cards, 1994, 1996 (Box 13, Folder 9)
      - Hopkins, Harry, 1945, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 10)
      - Hughes, Carol, regarding article, 1951 (Box 13, Folder 11)
      - Johns Hopkins Hospital, 1982-1996 (Box 13, Folder 12)
      - Kluger, Richard, 1978-1987 (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - Leeds Castle Foundation, 1982-1985 (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - Light, Richard U., 1990-1994 (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - Lineaweaver, Mrs. Charles P., 1960-1964 (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - Margaret, Princess, Countess of Snowdon, 1954 (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - Merrick, Beverly, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1983-1994 (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - Morgan, Ted, 1982-1985 (Box 15, Folder 7)
      - Mount Holyoke Art Advisory Committee tour of Greentree, 1984 April 28 (Box 15, Folder 8)
      - Museum of Modern Art, 1983-1996 (Box 15, Folder 9)
      - National Gallery of Art, 1990-1996 (Box 15, Folder 10)
      - National Museum of Racing, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 11)
      - Naujoks, Kurt, 1991-1997 (Box 15, Folder 12)
      - New York Hospital/Cornell Medical Center, 1979-1997 (Box 15, Folder 13)
      - New York Herald Tribune, International Herald Tribune, 1969-1998 (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - Nixon, Patricia, 1958-1960 (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - North Shore University Hospital, 1984-1997 (Box 16, Folder 3-5)
      - Nuland, Sherwin, 1968, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 6)
      - Nutting, Anthony, Undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
      - Obituaries and service, 1998 (Box 16, Folder 8)
      - O'Hara, Patricia, Undated (Box 16, Folder 9)
      - Ormandy, Eugene, 1964-1965 (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - Paley, Barbara Cushing, death of (sister), 1978-1984 (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - Paley, William Cushing (nephew), 1987 (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - Paley, William S. (brother-in-law), 1984-1987 (Box 17, Folder 4)
      - Parish, Dorothy May, 1991-1995 (Box 17, Folder 5)
      - Payne Whitney Court Tennis Tournament, 1982-1994 (Box 17, Folder 6)
      - Payson family, 1986-1998 (Box 17, Folder 7)
      - Payson, Joan Whitney, Circa 1940-1950 (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - Pillar of New York State Award, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 9)
      - Political, 1952-1956, undated (Box 17, Folder 10)
      - Pope, Bonnie, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - Publications about, 1986-1993 (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - Rainier III, Prince of Monaco, Undated (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - Reagan, Nancy and Ronald, 1986-1987 (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - Reorganization of Room 4600, 1982-1983 (Box 19, Folder 3)
      - Rewald, John, 1953-1995 (Box 19, Folder 4-5)
      - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1945, 1961 (Box 19, Folder 6)
      - Royal Academy Trust, American Associates of the, 1984-1997 (Box 19, Folder 7)
      - Royal Family (Windsor), 1982-1997 (Box 19, Folder 8)
      - Royal Family (Windsor), the Queen's visit to Greentree Stud Farm, 1984 October (Box 19, Folder 9)
      - Saratoga, 1992 August (Box 19, Folder 10)
      - Scherr, Lawrence and Peggy, 1983-1993 (Box 19, Folder 11)
      - Schmidt, Benno and Nancy, 1984-1996 (Box 19, Folder 12)
      - Seitz, Raymond G. H., 1993-1996 (Box 19, Folder 13)
      - Selznick, David O., papers, 1981-1995 (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - Sitwell, Edith and Osbert, 1950-1964 (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - Straight, Daphne, 1948-1973 (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - Symington family, 1983-1997 (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - Terrill, Eric Beard, Jr., 1972 (Box 20, Folder 5)
      - Thompson, Elizabeth, 1977-1992 (Box 20, Folder 6)
      - Tippett, Elizabeth (Altemus) Whitney (first wife of John Hay Whitney), 1937-1989 (Box 20, Folder 7)
      - Tree, Jeremy, 1982-1993 (Box 20, Folder 8)
      - United Cerebral Palsy Humanitarian Award, 1961-1964 (Box 20, Folder 9)
      - Venetian Room, 1998 (Box 20, Folder 10)
      - Wald, Richard C., 1976-1997 (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Walpole Society, 1985-1987 (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Wenk, Lizzie, Undated (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Whitney Communications Company, 1982-1995 (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Whitney, John Hay, Circa 1950-1970 (Box 22, Folder 2-3)
      - Whitney, John Hay, Journalism Award, 1982-1991 (Box 22, Folder 4-5)
      - Whittacker, Allison, 1986-1992 (Box 22, Folder 6)
      - Wisner, Frank, 1983-1988 (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - Woodhams, Edgar, 1983-1990 (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - Yale University
        - General, 1972-1997 (Box 22, Folder 9-10)
        - Axion Research Foundation, 1991-1996 (Box 23, Folder 1)
        - Cushing-Whitney Medical Library
          - General, 1983-1998 (Box 23, Folder 2-3)
          - Bookplate, 1986 (Box 23, Folder 4)
          - Dedication, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 5-6)
          - Harvey Cushing Papers, 1982-1991 (Box 23, Folder 7)
          - Restoration and expansion, preliminary reports, 1988-1990 (Box 23, Folder 8)
        - Medical School, 1989-1997 (Box 24, Folder 1)
        - Movies for Yale Crew, 1966-1998 (Box 24, Folder 2)
        - Payne Whitney Gymnasium, 1991 (Box 24, Folder 3)
        - Whitney Humanities Center, 1978-1995 (Box 24, Folder 4)
      - Ziegler, Laura, Undated (Box 24, Folder 5)
      - Zuckerman, Solly and Joan, 1961-1972 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Whitney, John Hay
      - General, 1934-1978, undated (Box 24, Folder 7)
      - American Magazine profile, 1940 (Box 24, Folder 8)
      - Astor, (William) Vincent, 1956 (Box 24, Folder 9)
      - Awards
        - Benjamin Franklin Medal, 1963 (Box 25, Folder 1)
        - Columbia University honorary degree, 1965 (Box 25, Folder 2)
        - Declined/regrets, 1958-1969 (Box 25, Folder 3)
        - Distinguished Citizens Award, Nassau County, 1961 (Box 25, Folder 4)
        - The Hundred Year Association Medal, 1953 (Box 25, Folder 5-6)
        - Kenyon College honorary degree, 1953 (Box 25, Folder 7)
        - Most Excellent Order of the British Empire, 1947-1948 (Box 25, Folder 8)
        - Nieman Foundation dinner, 1963 (Box 25, Folder 9)
        - Order of St. John, knighthood, 1961 (Box 25, Folder 10)
        - Tuition Plan Incorporated, award, 1956 (Box 25, Folder 11)
      - Benton, William, 1946-1964 (Box 26, Folder 1)
      - Biographical inquiries, 1959-1982 (Box 26, Folder 2)
      - Birthday greetings
        - 1953-1978 (Box 27, Folder 1-6)
        - 1979-1981 (Box 28, Folder 1-3)
      - Brewster, Kingman, 1964-1965, 1975-1981 (Box 29, Folder 1)
        Includes Whitney's remarks about retiring from the Yale Corporation and reflections on his service to the University.
      - Brooks School, Whitney Scholars, 1957-1981 (Box 29, Folder 2)
      - Brown University honorary degree, 1958 (Box 29, Folder 3)
      - Citizens for Eisenhower, 1951-1956 (Box 29, Folder 4-9)
        Contains fundraising letters including correspondence to Dwight D. Eisenhower about addressing women as a significant voter block.
      - Citizens Non-Partisan Committee, 1953 (Box 29, Folder 10)
      - Christ Church in Manhasset, New York, 1965 (Box 29, Folder 11)
      - Christmas greetings, 1954-1981 (Box 30, Folder 1-7)
      - Coke, Henry C., Jr., 1940-1978 (Box 31, Folder 1)
      - De Roulet Family, 1963-1975 (Box 31, Folder 2)
      - Distinguished persons, 1927-1953 (Box 31, Folder 3)
        Includes letters from Archbishop Francis Spellman, J. Edgar Hoover, and William O. Douglas.
      - Dulles, John Foster, 1953-1954 (Box 31, Folder 4)
      - Eaker, Ira, 1955-1976 (Box 31, Folder 5)
      - Eisenhower, Dwight D.
        - General, 1953-1968 (Box 31, Folder 6-10)
          Includes personal correspondence as well as discussions about political strategies.
        - Campaign, 1952 (Box 31, Folder 11)
        - Inauguration, 1957 (Box 31, Folder 12)
        - Death of, 1969, 1976 (Box 31, Folder 13)
      - Eisenhower Mall project, 1965 (Box 32, Folder 1)
      - Elwes, Simon, 1962-1964 (Box 32, Folder 2)
      - Fairbanks, Douglas, 1960-1980 (Box 32, Folder 3)
      - Family, general, 1917, 1952-1981 (Box 33, Folder 1)
      - Film ventures, 1933-1979 (Box 33, Folder 2)
        Contains letters about Technicolor investments.
      - Fortune profile, 1963-1964 (Box 33, Folder 3)
      - Fosburgh family, 1966, 1971 (Box 33, Folder 4)
      - French Legion, 1952 (Box 33, Folder 5)
      - Friends, 1956-1982
        - A (Box 33, Folder 6-9)
        - B (Box 34, Folder 1-6)
        - C-D (Box 35, Folder 1-7)
        - E-G (Box 36, Folder 1-5)
        - H-K (Box 37, Folder 1-7)
        - L-N (Box 38, Folder 1-7)
        - O-R (Box 39, Folder 1-6)
        - S (Box 40, Folder 1-5)
        - T-Z (Box 41, Folder 1-7)
      - Garey, Robert H, 1959-1976 (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Genealogy inquiries, 1939, 1970-1976 (Box 42, Folder 2)
      - Gone with the Wind, 1940, 1967, 1971 (Box 42, Folder 3)
        Includes letters from Margaret Mitchell, Laurence Olivier, and Kay Brown Barrett.
      - Griswold, Alfred, 1959-1963 (Box 42, Folder 4)
      - Groton School, 1956-1974 (Box 42, Folder 5)
      - Guion, Connie, 1956-1971 (Box 42, Folder 6)
      - Hardwicke, Earl of, 1961-1971 (Box 42, Folder 7)
      - Hay, Clarence and Alice, family, Circa 1960-1980 (Box 42, Folder 8)
      - Hay, John M.
        - Biography, 1975 (Box 42, Folder 9)
        - Inquiries, Circa 1930-1969 (Box 42, Folder 10)
        - John Hay Center, 1971 (Box 42, Folder 11)
        - Papers, 1972-1980 (Box 42, Folder 12)
      - Henry, Barkie, 1956-1968 (Box 42, Folder 13)
      - Jackson, William H., 1951-1976 (Box 42, Folder 14-15)
      - Javits, Jacob, 1956-1980 (Box 43, Folder 1-2)
      - Kennedy family, 1961-1976 (Box 43, Folder 3)
      - Lindsay, John V., 1970-1972 (Box 43, Folder 4)
      - Lindsay, John V., mayoral campaign, 1965, 1969 (Box 43, Folder 5-6)
        Includes personal fundraising letters.
      - Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1952, 1961, 1981 (Box 43, Folder 7)
      - Luce, Henry, 1957-1964 (Box 43, Folder 8)
      - MacMillan, Harold, 1961-1966, 1981 (Box 43, Folder 9)
      - McClain, John, 1960-1967 (Box 43, Folder 10)
      - McCrary family, 1950-1968 (Box 43, Folder 11-12)
      - Mellon, Paul, 1963-1976 (Box 43, Folder 13)
      - Mory's Cup, 1965 (Box 44, Folder 1)
      - Murphy, James L., 1956-1981 (Box 44, Folder 2)
      - Museum of Modern Art
        - General, 1958-1980 (Box 44, Folder 3)
        - Film library
          - Origins, 1935, 1950-1955, 1997 (Box 44, Folder 4)
          - Steering Committee, 1968-1979 (Box 44, Folder 5)
        - Investment Committee, 1966-1972 (Box 44, Folder 6)
      - National Gallery of Art
        - General, 1966-1981 (Box 44, Folder 7-9)
        - Finance Committee, 1937-1971 (Box 44, Folder 10)
      - New York Hospital
        - General, 1966-1982 (Box 45, Folder 1)
        - Bicentennial, 1968-1970 (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - The New Yorker profile, 1951 (Box 45, Folder 3)
      - Nixon, Richard M., 1954-1955, 1962-1970 (Box 45, Folder 4-5)
        Contains excerpts of speeches given by Nixon and correspondence outlining John Hay Whitney's concerns about Nixon's political future.
      - North Shore University Hospital, 1967-1979 (Box 46, Folder 1-2)
      - Oxford University, 1926 (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Paley family, 1957-1977 (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - Payson family, 1923, 1963-1986 (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - Payson, Charles, 1968-1978 (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - Payson, Joan Whitney, 1965-1972 (Box 47, Folder 5)
      - Payson, Joan Whitney, death, 1975 (Box 47, Folder 6)
      - Political, 1954-1981 (Box 47, Folder 7-9)
        Includes correspondence about national Republican candidates.
      - Ripon Society, 1969-1974 (Box 47, Folder 10)
      - Rockefeller, Nelson A., family, 1952-1973 (Box 47, Folder 11)
      - Rockefeller for President, 1968 (Box 48, Folder 1)
      - Rothschild, Lord, 1963-1971 (Box 48, Folder 2)
      - Royal visit: The Princess Margaret and the Earl of Snowdon, 1965 (Box 48, Folder 3)
      - Rusk, Dean, 1961-1962 (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - St. Bernard's School, 1973-1974 (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - Saturday Evening Post profile, 1957 (Box 49, Folder 2)
      - Schmidt, Benno, 1961-1981 (Box 49, Folder 3)
      - Selznick family, 1932-1980 (Box 49, Folder 4)
      - Sheffield, Joseph, 1952-1973 (Box 49, Folder 5)
      - Spivack, Sydney Shepherd, 1949-1969 (Box 49, Folder 6)
      - Stephens Collection, 1974-1975 (Box 49, Folder 7-8)
      - Straight family, 1953-1997 (Box 49, Folder 9)
      - Symington family, 1956-1981 (Box 50, Folder 1-2)
      - Thoroughbred Club of America, 1938 (Box 50, Folder 3)
      - Thoroughbred Racing Assocation, 1951 (Box 50, Folder 4)
      - United Service to China Fellowship, 1949 (Box 50, Folder 5)
      - Vogue profile, 1964, 1983 (Box 50, Folder 6)
      - Wadsworth family, 1960-1980 (Box 50, Folder 7)
      - Wald, Richard, 1970-1978 (Box 50, Folder 8)
      - Weaver, Robert, 1961-1968 (Box 50, Folder 9)
      - Wedding to Betsey Cushing Whitney, 1942 (Box 50, Folder 10)
      - Whitney, Helen Hay
        - General, Circa 1920, 1942 (Box 51, Folder 1)
        - Funeral, 1944-1954, undated (Box 51, Folder 2)
        - Headstone, 1944, 1963 (Box 51, Folder 3)
      - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1977-1983 (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - William S. Paley Charitable Trust, 1968-1971 (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - Williams, Langbourne M., 1942-1980 (Box 52, Folder 3)
      - Windsor family, 1966-1981 (Box 52, Folder 4)
      - Woodhams, Edgar, 1942-1982 (Box 52, Folder 5)
      - Yale University
        - General, 1967-1982 (Box 52, Folder 6-8)
        - Board memberships and resignations, 1932-1957, 1973-1979 (Box 53, Folder 1-2)
        - Brewster, Kingman, 1964-1977 (Box 53, Folder 3-4)
          Includes discussions of the 1970 May Day student demonstrations and alumni reaction.
        - Committee on Paul Mellon Center for British Art, 1972-1973 (Box 53, Folder 5)
        - Corporation, 1955-1973 (Box 53, Folder 6)
        - Donation of John Hay Whitney papers, 1982-1986 (Box 53, Folder 7)
        - Honorary degree committee, 1971 (Box 53, Folder 8)
        - John Hay Whitney Professorship in the Humanities, 1976-1981 (Box 53, Folder 9)
        - Land gift, 1955-1981 (Box 54, Folder 1-3)
        - Payne Whitney Gymnasium, 1927-1946 (Box 54, Folder 4)
        - Residential colleges, construction and renovation, 1970-1977 (Box 54, Folder 5-7)
        - School of Art, School of Architecture, 1970-1971 (Box 55, Folder 1)
        - Sigerist, Henry, 1947, 1951 (Box 55, Folder 2)